<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Code-review | /trasteando/]]></title>
  <link href="http://rojoangel.github.io/blog/categories/code-review/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://rojoangel.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-27T23:59:41+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://rojoangel.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Angel Rojo]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What to Look for in a Code Review - by Trisha Gee @ JetBrains Upsource Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://rojoangel.github.io/blog/2015/09/27/what-to-look-for-in-a-code-review/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-27T20:24:13+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://rojoangel.github.io/blog/2015/09/27/what-to-look-for-in-a-code-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve just read this post about <a href="http://blog.jetbrains.com/upsource/2015/07/23/what-to-look-for-in-a-code-review/">What to look for in a Code Review</a>.</p>

<p>These are notes to myself.</p>

<p>Automatize these:</p>

<ul>
<li>Formatting</li>
<li>Style</li>
<li>Naming</li>
<li>Test coverage</li>
</ul>


<p>Instead look for:</p>

<p><strong>Design</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Fit with the overall architecture?</li>
<li>SOLID principles, Domain Driven Design</li>
<li>Design patterns used. Are these appropriate?</li>
<li>Does this new code follow the current practices? Is the code migrating in the correct direction?</li>
<li>Is the code in the right place?</li>
<li>Could the new code have reused something in the existing code? Does the new code provide something we can reuse in the existing code? Does the new code introduce duplication?</li>
<li>Is the code over-engineered? YAGNI?</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Readability &amp; Maintainability</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Do the names actually reflect the thing they represent?</li>
<li>Can I understand what the code does by reading it?</li>
<li>Can I understand what the tests do?</li>
<li>Do the tests cover a good subset of cases? Do they cover happy paths and exceptional cases? Are there cases that haven’t been considered?</li>
<li>Are the exception error messages understandable?</li>
<li>Are confusing sections of code either documented, commented, or covered by understandable tests (according to team preference)?</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Functionality</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Does the code actually do what it was supposed to do? Do the tests really test the code meets the agreed requirements?</li>
<li>Does the code look like it contains subtle bugs, like using the wrong variable for a check, or accidentally using an and instead of an or?</li>
</ul>


<p><strong>Have you thought about…?</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>Security</li>
<li>Regulatory requirements that need to be met?</li>
<li>Does the new code introduce avoidable performance issues</li>
<li>Does the author need to create public documentation, or change existing one?</li>
<li>Have user-facing messages been checked for correctness?</li>
<li>Are there obvious errors that will stop this working in production?</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
